Register of the Raymond Moley papers, 1902-1971
Hoover Institution Archives
- FRANKLIN D. ROOSEVELT FILE, SCHEDULE A. (Boxes 282-292)
  - Speeches, 1920-1936
    - Speech, Boston, Massachusetts, October 31, 1932 (Folder 10-11)
    - Speech, New York City, New York, November 3, 1932 (Folder 12)
    - Speech, Brooklyn, New York, November 4, 1932
      - Holograph annotated drafts (Box 289, Folder 1)
      - Clippings (Folder 2)
    - Speech, New York City, New York, Madison Square Garden, November 5, 1932 (Folder 3)
    - Speech, Poughkeepsie, New York, November 7, 1932 (Folder 4)
    - Inaugural address, Washington, D.C., March 4, 1933 (Folder 5)
    - Message to Congress requesting drastic economies in government, March 10, 1933 (Folder 6)
    - Radio address on banking, March 12, 1933 (Folder 7)
    - Radio address, May 7, 1933 (Folder 8)
    - Message to the nations of the world, May 16, 1933 (Folder 9)
    - Message to Congress to enact the National Industrial Recovery Act, May 17, 1933 (Folder 10)
    - Speech, Chicago, Illinois, October 2, 1933 (Folder 11)
    - Radio address, October 22, 1933 (Folder 12)
    - Message to Congress, January 3, 1934 (Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous speeches, Spring 1934 (Folder 14)
    - Notes for speeches delivered between June and August 1934 (Folder 15)
    - Message to Congress, June 8, 1934 (Folder 16)
    - Speech, Yale University, June 21, 1934 (Folder 17)
    - Radio address, June 28, 1934 (Folder 18)
    - Speeches, Hawaii and Panama, July 11, 28, 1934 (Folder 19)
    - Speech, Glacier National Park, Montana, August 5, 1934 (Folder 20)
    - Speech, Ft. Peck Dam, Montana, August 6, 1934 (Folder 21)
    - Speech, Rochester, Minnesota, August 8, 1934 (Folder 22)
    - Speech, Green Bay, Wisconsin, August 9, 1934 (Folder 23)
    - Radio address, September 30, 1934 (Folder 24)
    - Speech, William and Mary College, October 20, 1934 (Box 290, Folder 1)
    - Speech, Washington, D.C., Bankers Speech, October 24, 1934 (Folder 2)
    - Speech, The Hermitage, Tennessee, November 12, 1934 (not given) (Folder 3)
    - Speech, December 24, 1934 (Folder 4)
    - Messages to Congress, January and February 1935 (Folder 5)
    - Message to Congress, January 4, 1935 (Folder 6)
    - Message to Congress on social security, January 17, 1935 (Folder 7)
    - Message to Congress on natural resources, January 24, 1935 (Folder 8)
    - Message to Congress on air transportation, January 31, 1935 (Folder 9)
    - Message to Congress on N.R.A. extention, February 20, 1935 (Folder 10)
    - Message to Congress on merchant marine, March 4, 1935 (Folder 11)
    - Message to Congress on public utility holding companies, March 12, 1935 (Folder 12)
    - Radio address, April 28, 1935 (Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous speech material, May 14, 1935 (Folder 14)
    - Speech, Washington, D.C., May 14, 1935 (Folder 15)
    - Message to Congress vetoing Bonus Bill, May 22, 1935
      - Memoranda and notes (Folder 16-17)
      - Memoranda (Box 291, Folder 1)
    - Message to Congress on transportation, June 7, 1935 (Folder 2)
    - Message to Congress on taxation, June 20, 1935 (Folder 3)
    - Speech, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, August 24, 1935 (Folder 4)
    - Speech, Fremont, Nebraska, September 28, 1935 (Folder 5)
    - Speech, Boulder Dam, September 30, 1935 (Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous notes for speeches made on western trip, September -October 1935 (Folder 7)
    - Speech, Los Angeles, California, October 1, 1935 (Folder 8)
    - Speech, San Diego, California, October 3, 1935 (Folder 9)
    - Message sent to Herald Tribune Citizenship Conference, October 18, 1935 (Folder 10)
    - Speech, Atlanta, Georgia, November 29, 1935 (Folder 11)
    - Speech, Chicago, Illinois, December 9, 1935 (Folder 12)
    - Speech, Notre Dame University, December 9, 1935 (Folder 13)
    - Message to Congress, January 4, 1936 (Folder 14)
    - Speech, Washington, D.C., January 8, 1936 (Folder 15)
    - Speech, New York City, New York, April 25, 1936 (Folder 16)
    - Acceptance speech at Democratic National Convention, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, June 27, 1936 (Folder 17)
  - Clippings and printed matter
    - General (Box 292, Folder 1)
    - 1932 Campaign, July-November (Folder 2-6)
    - Democratic rebuttal of the Secretary of Treasury, November 1932 (Folder 7)
    - Special inaugural editions (Folder 8)
  - Miscellany (Folder 9)
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE. (Tape cabinet)
  Three phonotapes of interviews of Raymond Moley, 1970, relating to Franklin D. Roosevelt, The First New Deal and Moley's diary
  - Sound recordings of interviews of Raymond Moley, 1970 February 16 - April 8 (Tape cabinet)
    Use copy reference numbers: 68008_a_0002058, 68008_a_0002059, 68008_a_0002060, 68008_a_0002070
    Relates to Franklin D. Roosevelt, The First New Deal, important persons, Moley's appointment to the Department of State, the Roosevelt cabinet, the first New Deal, and Moley's diary. Interviews conducted in New York City and Stanford, California.
    Tape 1 (68008_a_0002058): Interview with Raymond Moley, 18 Mar 1970 - 19 Mar 1970, New York City. Comments re diary. Also R. Moley, New York City, 8 Apr 1970. FDR-RM relationship.
    Tape 2 (68008_a_0002059): Interview with Raymond Moley in Hoover Inst. 16 Feb 1970. Notes on his 1966 book and important persons. Also R.Moley in New York City 18 Mar 1970
    Tape 3 (68008_a_0002060): Interview with Raymond Moley, 8 Apr 1970; FDR-RM relationship. Concerns Moley's appointment to the Department of State, the Roosevelt cabinet, and the first New Deal.
    Unnumbered tape (68008_a_0002070): Interview with Raymond Moley on 16 February 1970 at the Hoover Institution
- PHOTOGRAPHS., (94 photos / 5 envelopes (10.A-V)
  - 18 photos of Franklin D. Roosevelt at the 1932 Democratic Convention, during the 1932 Presidential Campaign, with Raymond Moley, and in Portrait pose (autographed) (Folder A)
    Includes photo of scenes from the Convention and the Campaign.
  - 7 photos of colleagues and acquaintances of Raymond Moley, including Alf Landon (autographed) Gus Hall (autographed), Robert LaFollette (autographed), Earl Warren (autographed), Eamon de Valera (autographed), and Herbert Hoover with a group, 1950 (Box B)
  - 15 photos of Raymond Moley and of colleagues, including James Farley and Thomas Dewey, and of F.D. Roosevelt during the 1932 campaign, including Florida assassination attempt, and with State Dept. officials and foreign delegations, and of F.D. Roosevelt in 1933, signed by Raymond Moley, Elliott Roosevelt, James Farley, Sam Rosenman and others (Folder mC)
  - 33 miscellaneous photos, 1950s (Box D)
    Includes photos of Goodwin Knight.
  - 20 miscellaneous photos, undated (Box E)
    Includes photo of William Jenning Bryan and of Barry Goldwater.
- INCREMENTAL MATERIALS (Box 293-294)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described. Contact us at hooverarchivesinfo@stanford.edu